We're going to practice observing
我们将进行一项练习，观察
the coronal dural sheath in relation to the symphysis and the
冠状硬膜鞘与耻骨联合和
maxilla.
上颌骨的关系。
We'll simply observe how these fields settle, but for that, you'll need to be
我们将简单地观察这些场是如何定位的，但在这里你需要
on an electrical level.
进入一个电学层面。
This is also how we treat tendons, tendinitis.
我们也是这样治疗肌腱和肌腱炎的。
change many things. As long as you haven't reset
改变很多事情。只要你没有重新连接
the electrical currents, it won't work.
电流，它就不会通过。
And when we see this placement
当我们看到这种定位时
of the base of the skull, which is the neurocranium
颅底，这是神经颅
in relation
相对于
to the viscerocranium. It's as if
内脏颅。就好像
your visceral system was supported
你的内脏系统被支撑着
at the base of the skull, like a
在颅底，就像一个
And above,
而在上面，
I have my brain
我有我的大脑
which is the neurocranium.
那是神经颅。
And between the two, I have this.
在这两者之间，我有这个。
And then, I can't
然后，我不知道
go directly to this base of the skull.
直接去颅底。
However, I can reach it through the periphery.
但是，我可以通过外围到达那里。
Since we know that all my
因为我们知道我所有的
dural membranes
硬脑膜膜
of tension all come
的张力都来
to attach to the base of my skull.
附着在我的颅底。
They are like moored.
它们就像被锚定了一样。
I will first take my
我将首先抓住我的
coronal suture and I will take
冠状缝，我将抓住
the part here that we call
这里我们称之为
the maxilla.
上颌骨的部分。
Okay?
好吗？
I'm putting myself on that level.
我把自己放在那个层面上。
Maxillo.
上颌。
zygomatic, actually, you see.
颧骨，实际上，你明白吗。
And I'll be there.
我会在那里。
And there, I also have a sheath, actually, that does this.
在那里，我也有一个鞘，实际上，它是这样的。
And which also comes, in fact, it's a line that also comes towards the base of the skull.
它也来了，实际上，这是一条也通向颅底的线。
They're like rings.
它们就像环一样。
The two rings must meet and be in connection, if you will, you see.
这两个环必须相遇并连接，如果你愿意，你明白吗。
And the electrical level is a subtle level where it's like it's on or off, actually.
而电学层面是一个微妙的层面，就像是开或关，实际上。
Don't forget, this coronal suture is quite low, because there are many who are there.
请记住，这个冠状缝合线相当低，因为有很多都在那里。
We're going to go quite well on this coronal suture, where Bregma was.
我们将很好地处理这个冠状缝合线，也就是前囟所在的地方。
because if it's alive, there are thermal exchanges
因为如果它是活的，就存在热交换
there's still a heat that impacts
仍然有热量在影响
she can also feel it gently
她也能轻轻地感受到
there's a point a bit on the line
线上有一个点
where there's a small energy loss
能量有点流失
there, what you feel
就是这样，你现在感受到的
now, I'm going to make you feel
现在，我将让你感受
I'm going to put it on the electrical frequency
我将切换到电频率
there I put myself on this ring
我现在放在这个环上
there I have this connection
我有了这种连接
I go towards this spheno-basilar symphysis
我走向这个蝶骨-筛骨联合
so here I can already say
所以在这里我可以说
look, it's vital, it's warm
看，这是有活力的，是温暖的
responds. There is still a little work that will be done in this
回应。在这个运动中，仍然会有一点工作要做，我们拭目以待。我
movement here, we'll see. I
现在将与她的上颌-颧骨部分建立连接，
will now connect with the part of her maxillo-zygomatic
像这样，
here, like this,
它也朝向……就好像这两个环相遇了
which also comes towards... it's as if these two rings meet
实际上。所以两者之间已经有区别了，上面已经有一些损失了，所以
actually. So already between
仍然有一些……
the two there is a difference, there is already a bit of a loss at the top, so
疲劳，有挣扎。现在，我立刻感觉到她的肾上腺。即使我在这里，也存在间接的肾上腺关系。所以在这里，需要给这位女士的电池充充电。
batteries
电池
for madam. For example, here, when I'm there and I feel that in consultation, right
这位女士。例如，当我在咨询中感受到这些时，我立刻会关注她的肾上腺，并温暖它们。我
release
释放
the ligaments here and I would put myself like this to recharge
这里的韧带，我会像这样放置以给肾上腺充电。
Afterwards, we will make the connection with the entire cardiac system,
之后，我们将与整个心脏系统建立联系，
so the entire endothelial system,
也就是整个内皮系统，
how we can work on the four entry points,
我们如何才能作用于四个入口，
which are the left and right internal carotid,
它们是左右颈内动脉，
and left and right vertebral, then the basilar system,
以及左右椎动脉，然后是基底动脉系统，
with how reactive they are,
以及它们如何反应，
if we touch them correctly,
如果我们正确地触诊它们，
and that we can release them in relation to the heart,
并且我们可以相对于心脏释放它们，
or sometimes in relation to the heart.
或者有时相对于心脏。
even to the vitelline umbilical system, so mesenteric
甚至到脐带卵黄系统，也就是肠系膜
or splenic on the sinus of the heart.
或脾脏在心脏窦上。
I work with four energies, with the energy of weight or gravity,
我使用四种能量工作，即重力或引力能量，
to restore a proper contact. Either some people are too heavy, they are already buried, or some people are even too light, they float. Then the energy of the midline, then the energy of the energetic body. pure. Here we are more on this electrical plane. What we feel is vibratory. And here again coronal. I wait and then I will see again here. Here again, I already have more vitality. It's not yet 100% but it's already better. There was a void. So it's the hammock of the eye. There, you see, there was a strain. The entire upper axis, so everything was in strain. There, who would that be? Do you feel that? It's as if it made a... I'm exaggerating, but it was like that. When I recognized the tissue, it has its reference point. There is induction. There is movement in ease. I'm not in movement in ease, I'm in presence. OK, first level. Second level, I'm going to work canino, maxillo, three fingers. At the level of my frontal boss. I have an axis like this. I need good support points, otherwise my hand will be unbalanced. There, I feel again. If I feel this warmth and this vibration, and if it's well in the plane. I'm looking for my frontal boss. There, which is here. I look. I stay here. Now, I'm here. There, I take at the same time the line here, and at the same time the line here. You see, the zygomatico-frontal boss line homolateral. So like that, I have two levels. Here, I have a good warmth, I have a good field. Here, it's more diminished. I'm going to look here, at the level of the coronal suture. I'm going to palpate my coronal suture, there, here, there, it's quite, there, here, just a little bit it can block a bit sometimes it makes a canine-maxillary nail here frontal and like that There, it passes. It's not yet how I would like it on the right. I'm looking. As I would like, as... Here, on the other side. Canine, canine. Axillo. Frontal, here, start. And then, here, and there. There's really... It's this axis here that's disturbed. So there's an energy loss here. Maybe it's slower to work. That's why it will heal faster. So here, what I've found each time, it's always in this axis. A bit of a loss of vitality, so to speak. And a bit on the coronal structure that I had a little bit at the beginning that was busy looking. So it's busy rebalancing like that. Third level, which we're doing now, renunciation of flexion. The mastoids. You shouldn't press too hard. There, she has a mastoid, she has a small torsion like that. One is a bit more anterior than the other, if you will. I'm going to see if it's a point of change and balance. And there, I can go into induction or facilitated movement. Here, it's a technique of slight induction. I follow her extension. Oops, she goes into flexion. And I accompany her flexion. And there, I press. When I put myself in these things, here, I observe her breathing. And if I want to go into a point of change, I observe her expiratory pause. Sometimes, people make a... Subtitling Radio-Canada What is that? Change of polarity. They take an inspiration and a big breath. So they make an oxidation, a change of redox.
以恢复正确的接触。
pure. Here we are more on this electrical plane. What we feel is vibratory. And
纯粹的。这里我们更多地处于这种电平面。我们感受到的这种是振动的。而且
here again
这里
coronal. I wait and then I will see again here. Here again,
再次冠状。我等待，然后我将在这里再次看到。这里
I already have more
再次，我已经有了更多的
vitality. It's not yet 100% but it's already better. There was a void. So
活力。它还没有达到100%，但已经好多了。之前有一个空虚。所以
it's the hammock of
这是
the eye. There, you see, there was a strain. The entire upper axis,
眼睛的吊床。你看，有一个张力。整个上轴
so everything was in strain.
所以一切都处于张力中。
There, who would that be? Do you feel that?
好了，这里，那会是谁？你感觉到吗？
It's as if it made a...
就像它形成了一个……
I'm exaggerating, but it was like that.
我夸张了，但就是那样。
When I recognized the tissue,
当我识别出组织时，
it has its reference point.
它有它的参考点。
There is induction.
有诱导。
There is movement in ease.
有促进运动。
I'm not in movement in ease,
我不在促进运动中，
I'm in presence.
我处于临在之中。
OK, first level.
好的，第一层。
Second level, I'm going to work
第二层，我将工作
canino, maxillo,
犬齿，上颌，
three fingers.
三根手指。
At the level of my frontal boss.
在我的额骨隆起处。
I have an axis like this.
我有一个这样的轴。
I need good support points,
我必须有好的支撑点，
otherwise my hand will be unbalanced.
否则我的手会失去平衡。
There, I feel again.
现在，我再次感觉到。
If I feel this warmth and this vibration,
如果我感觉到这种温暖和振动，
and if it's well in the plane.
而且它正好在平面内。
I'm looking for my frontal boss.
我仔细寻找我的额骨隆起。
There, which is here.
好了，就在这里。
I look.
我看着。
I stay here.
我留在这里。
Now, I'm here.
现在，我在这里。
There, I take at the same time the line here,
在这里，我同时取这条线，
and at the same time the line here.
同时取这条线。
You see, the zygomatico-frontal boss line
你看，颧骨-额骨隆起线
homolateral.
同侧。
So like that, I have two levels.
这样我就有两个层面。
Here, I have a good warmth, I have a good field.
这里，我有很好的热量，很好的场。
Here, it's more diminished.
这里，它减少了。
I'm going to look here, at the level of the coronal suture.
我将在这里，在冠状缝合线处查看。
I'm going to palpate my coronal suture, there, here, there,
我将触诊我的冠状缝合线，就在这里
it's quite, there, here, just a little bit
这里有点，就在这里，一点点
it can block a bit
它可能会有点堵塞
sometimes it makes a canine-maxillary nail
有时它会发出犬齿-上颌骨的咔嗒声
here frontal and like that
这里是额骨，就这样
There, it passes.
好了，它通过了。
It's not yet how I would like it on the right.
它还没有达到我想要的右侧。
I'm looking.
我在寻找。
As I would like, as...
就像我想要的，就像...
Here, on the other side.
在这里，在另一边。
Canine, canine.
犬齿，犬齿。
Axillo.
上颌骨。
Frontal, here, start.
额骨，这里，起点。
And then, here, and there.
然后，这里，和那里。
There's really...
真的有...
It's this axis here that's disturbed.
是这个轴线受到了干扰。
So there's an energy loss here.
所以这里有能量损失。
Maybe it's slower to work.
也许工作起来会更慢。
That's why it will heal faster.
这就是为什么它会更快愈合。
So here, what I've found each time, it's always in this axis.
所以在这里，我每次都发现，每次都在这个轴线上。
A bit of a loss of vitality, so to speak.
活力有点丧失，引号。
And a bit on the coronal structure that I had a little bit
以及冠状结构上我有点
at the beginning that was busy looking.
一开始就在寻找的。
So it's busy rebalancing like that.
所以它正在重新平衡。
Third level, which we're doing now,
第三个层面，我们现在做的，
renunciation of flexion.
屈曲的放弃。
The mastoids.
乳突。
You shouldn't press too hard.
不要按得太用力。
There, she has a mastoid, she has a small torsion like that.
看，她有一个乳突，她有一个这样的小扭曲。
One is a bit more anterior than the other, if you will.
如果你愿意，有一个比另一个更靠前一点。
I'm going to see if it's a point of change and balance.
我将看看这是否是一个变化和平衡点。
And there, I can go into induction or facilitated movement.
然后，我可以进行诱导或促进运动。
Here, it's a technique of slight induction.
这里，是一个轻柔的诱导技术。
I follow her extension.
我是它的延伸。
Oops, she goes into flexion.
看，它开始屈曲。
And I accompany her flexion.
我伴随它的屈曲。
And there, I press.
然后，我按压。
When I put myself in these things, here,
当我做这些事情时，
I observe her breathing.
我观察它的呼吸。
And if I want to go into a point of change,
如果我想进入一个转变点，
I observe her expiratory pause.
我观察它的呼气末期。
Sometimes, people make a...
有时，人们会……
Subtitling Radio-Canada
加拿大广播公司字幕
What is that?
那是什么？
Change of polarity.
极性改变。
They take an inspiration and a big breath.
他们吸气，然后深呼一口气。
So they make an oxidation, a change of redox.
所以他们进行氧化，一个氧化还原的改变。